uclaextension.edu 2013-12-28

# UCLA Extension: Privacy Policy

UCLA Extension is committed to respecting your privacy. In general, you can visit uclaextension.edu without revealing any personal information. If you fill out one of our request or survey forms, we may ask you for personal information, such as your name, address, phone number, and email address so we may send you materials based on interests you indicate. Should you choose to provide us with any personal information, such as age or level of education, you can be assured that UCLA Extension will only use it in the aggregate. We do not and will never sell or rent your mailing address, email address, or any other data that can personally identify you in any way to an outside group. 

**Information We Collect for Course Enrollment Purposes**   
UCLA Extension allows students to register for courses through our website. Online registration requires that some personal information and payment card information be transmitted via the web.  Furnishing all information designated by an asterisk as _required_ on the forms on this site is a condition of enrollment.  (Date of birth, gender, Social Security number (SSN), and ethnic identity are not required fields.)  Failure to provide required information will delay, or may even prevent, your enrollment. 

  * If you do not have or could not provide us with your SSN, you will be permitted to enroll; however, UCLA Extension will not be able to provide the IRS with evidence of fee payments that might entitle you to tax credits provided under the Taxpayer Relief Act of 1997.  Each year in December, UCLA Extension will conduct an annual solicitation of students whose records are subject to IRS reporting but where the SSN field remains blank, this to ensure that an oversight on your part can be addressed. You may amend your record online at any time by logging in to _MyExtension_ , or submit [_IRS form W-9S_](http://www.irs.gov/pub/irs-pdf/fw9s.pdf)by mail to UCLA Extension Records Office, 10995 Le Conte Avenue Room 113, Los Angeles, CA 90024. 
  * UCLA Extension routinely reports its student census to the National Student Clearinghouse. Those seeking deferments for repayment of student loans may wish to provide SSN to expedite the deferment process. 
  * Consistent with California statute of limitations for amending tax returns, UCLA Extension’s interest in retaining SSN for reporting purposes expires four years beyond the tax year. If still on file four years after your last enrollment, the first five characters of your SSN will be automatically expunged, leaving only the last four as an optional record identifier. SSN data are stored in an encrypted state. You may request at any time to have either or both elements of your SSN data deleted. 
  * Contact information furnished on these forms may be used by University departments and publicly announced program co-sponsors for distribution of information on future programs and activities of interest to you. This and other information will be transmitted to the state and federal government if required by law. UCLA Extension does not sell or otherwise share its mailing list.   
****

**Other Information We Collect**   
We use your IP address to help diagnose problems with our server and to administer our website. In this context, you as an individual remain anonymous. We may collect and distribute aggregate statistics about our website visitors, traffic patterns, and related site information. These statistics do not include any information that allows for identification of an individual in any manner. 

**Sending Your Information**   
We send materials to our students and those who express interest in UCLA Extension to help you stay abreast of our courses, programs, and special events. At any time, if you wish to be removed from our mailing lists, click [_here_](https://www.uclaextension.edu/pages/EmailUnsubscribe.aspx "link to unsubscribe.")and enter your mailing or email address and select the preferences that you no longer wish to receive, then click the "Unsubscribe" button. We will be happy to remove you from our contact list as you request. 

**Security**   
Data you enter during a visit to our site is stored on systems using appropriate physical, electronic, and management procedures to safeguard and secure all information we collect online. Any sensitive or personal data, such as credit card or purchase information that you enter for online enrollment purposes is transmitted in an encrypted form, then stored in an encrypted form, and requires the use of a secure browser for entry and recall. 

**Cookies**   
A cookie is a small "data" file stored on a user's hard drive. A cookie automatically identifies your browser to our server whenever you interact with us. We usually collect the domain name of the server from which you are visiting. Collecting this information does not allow us to personally identify you. We utilize cookies to gather aggregate information about how our site is being used, including pages visitors are viewing. Most cookies expire after a certain period of time. If you wish, you may set your browser to reject all cookies and still review our website. 

**Links to Other Sites**   
UCLA Extension website and newsletter may link to external sites outside of the UCLA Extension and University domain as a convenience to you. UCLA Extension is not responsible for the privacy procedures or the content of such sites, and does not make any representation about them.
